<?xml version="1.0"?>
<book
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../bits/BITS-2-1-XSD/BITS-book2-1.xsd">
    <book-meta>
        <book-title-group>
            <book-title>The Secret Adversary</book-title>
        </book-title-group>
        <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
                <name>
                    <surname>Christie</surname>
                    <given-names>Agatha</given-names>
                </name>
            </contrib>
        </contrib-group>
        <notes>
            <graphic specific-use="online" position="anchor"
   				xlink:href="https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/1155/images/cover.jpg">
                <alt-text>Cover art</alt-text>
<!--				<long-desc>The Secret Adversary cover art.</long-desc>-->
            </graphic>
            <p>TO ALL THOSE WHO LEAD MONOTONOUS LIVES</p>
			<p>IN THE HOPE THAT THEY MAY EXPERIENCE</p><p>AT SECOND HAND</p>
			<p>THE DELIGHTS AND DANGERS</p><p>OF ADVENTURE</p>
        </notes>
    </book-meta>
    <front-matter>
        <toc>
            <toc-title-group>
                <title>Contents</title>
            </toc-title-group>
            <toc-entry>
				<title>PROLOGUE</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc1"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER I. THE YOUNG ADVENTURERS, LTD.</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc2"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER II. MR. WHITTINGTON’S OFFER</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc3"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER III. A SET BACK</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc4"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER IV. WHO IS JANE FINN?</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc5"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER V. MR. JULIUS P. HERSHEIMMER</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc6"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER VI. A PLAN OF CAMPAIGN</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc7"/>
			</toc-entry>
			<toc-entry>
				<title>CHAPTER VII. THE HOUSE IN SOHO</title>
				<nav-pointer rid="tc8"/>
			</toc-entry>
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER VIII. THE ADVENTURES OF TOMMY</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc9"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER IX. TUPPENCE ENTERS DOMESTIC SERVICE</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc10"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER X. ENTER SIR JAMES PEEL EDGERTON</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc11"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XI. JULIUS TELLS A STORY</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc12"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XII. A FRIEND IN NEED </title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc13"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XIII. THE VIGIL</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc14"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XIV. A CONSULTATION</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc15"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XV. TUPPENCE RECEIVES A PROPOSAL</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc16"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XVI. FURTHER ADVENTURES OF TOMMY </title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc17"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XVII. ANNETTE</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc18"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XVIII. THE TELEGRAM</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc19"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XIX. JANE FINN</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc20"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XX. TOO LATE</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc21"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXI. TOMMY MAKES A DISCOVERY</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc22"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXII. IN DOWNING STREET</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc23"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXIII. A RACE AGAINST TIME</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc24"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXIV. JULIUS TAKES A HAND</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc25"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXV. JANE’S STORY</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc26"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXVI. MR. BROWN</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc27"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXVII. A SUPPER PARTY AT THE SAVOY</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc28"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
<!--			<toc-entry>-->
<!--				<title>CHAPTER XXVIII. AND AFTER</title>-->
<!--				<nav-pointer rid="tc29"/>-->
<!--			</toc-entry>-->
        </toc>
    </front-matter>
    <book-body>
		<book-part id="tc1">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>PROLOGUE</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>
		It was 2 p.m. on the afternoon of May 7, 1915. The Lusitania had been
		struck by two torpedoes in succession and was sinking rapidly, while the boats
		were being launched with all possible speed. The women and children were being
		lined up awaiting their turn. Some still clung desperately to husbands and
		fathers; others clutched their children closely to their breasts. One girl
		stood alone, slightly apart from the rest. She was quite young, not more than
		eighteen. She did not seem afraid, and her grave, steadfast eyes looked
		straight ahead.
		</p><p>
		“I beg your pardon.”
		</p><p>
		A man’s voice beside her made her start and turn. She had noticed the
		speaker more than once amongst the first-class passengers. There had been a
		hint of mystery about him which had appealed to her imagination. He spoke to no
		one. If anyone spoke to him he was quick to rebuff the overture. Also he had a
		nervous way of looking over his shoulder with a swift, suspicious glance.
		</p><p>
		She noticed now that he was greatly agitated. There were beads of perspiration
		on his brow. He was evidently in a state of overmastering fear. And yet he did
		not strike her as the kind of man who would be afraid to meet death!
		</p><p>
		“Yes?” Her grave eyes met his inquiringly.
		</p><p>
		He stood looking at her with a kind of desperate irresolution.
		</p><p>
		“It must be!” he muttered to himself. “Yes—it is the
		only way.” Then aloud he said abruptly: “You are an
		American?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes.”
		</p><p>
		“A patriotic one?”
		</p><p>
		The girl flushed.
		</p><p>
		“I guess you’ve no right to ask such a thing! Of course I
		am!”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t be offended. You wouldn’t be if you knew how much
		there was at stake. But I’ve got to trust some one—and it must be a
		woman.”
		</p><p>
		“Why?”
		</p><p>
		“Because of ‘women and children first.’” He looked
		round and lowered his voice. “I’m carrying papers—vitally
		important papers. They may make all the difference to the Allies in the war.
		You understand? These papers have got to be saved! They’ve more
		chance with you than with me. Will you take them?”
		</p><p>
		The girl held out her hand.
		</p><p>
		“Wait—I must warn you. There may be a risk—if I’ve been
		followed. I don’t think I have, but one never knows. If so, there will be
		danger. Have you the nerve to go through with it?”
		</p><p>
		The girl smiled.
		</p><p>
		“I’ll go through with it all right. And I’m real proud to be
		chosen! What am I to do with them afterwards?”
		</p><p>
		“Watch the newspapers! I’ll advertise in the personal column of the
		Times, beginning ‘Shipmate.’ At the end of three days if
		there’s nothing—well, you’ll know I’m down and out.
		Then take the packet to the American Embassy, and deliver it into the
		Ambassador’s own hands. Is that clear?”
		</p><p>
		“Quite clear.”
		</p><p>
		“Then be ready—I’m going to say good-bye.” He took her
		hand in his. “Good-bye. Good luck to you,” he said in a louder
		tone.
		</p><p>
		Her hand closed on the oilskin packet that had lain in his palm.
		</p><p>
		The Lusitania settled with a more decided list to starboard. In answer
		to a quick command, the girl went forward to take her place in the boat.

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc2">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER I.
		THE YOUNG ADVENTURERS, LTD.</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		“Tommy, old thing!”
		</p><p>
		“Tuppence, old bean!”
		</p><p>
		The two young people greeted each other affectionately, and momentarily blocked
		the Dover Street Tube exit in doing so. The adjective “old” was
		misleading. Their united ages would certainly not have totalled forty-five.
		</p><p>
		“Not seen you for simply centuries,” continued the young man.
		“Where are you off to? Come and chew a bun with me. We’re getting a
		bit unpopular here—blocking the gangway as it were. Let’s get out
		of it.”
		</p><p>
		The girl assenting, they started walking down Dover Street towards Piccadilly.
		</p><p>
		“Now then,” said Tommy, “where shall we go?”
		</p><p>
		The very faint anxiety which underlay his tone did not escape the astute ears
		of Miss Prudence Cowley, known to her intimate friends for some mysterious
		reason as “Tuppence.” She pounced at once.
		</p><p>
		“Tommy, you’re stony!”
		</p><p>
		“Not a bit of it,” declared Tommy unconvincingly. “Rolling in
		cash.”
		</p><p>
		“You always were a shocking liar,” said Tuppence severely,
		“though you did once persuade Sister Greenbank that the doctor had
		ordered you beer as a tonic, but forgotten to write it on the chart. Do you
		remember?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy chuckled.
		</p><p>
		“I should think I did! Wasn’t the old cat in a rage when she found
		out? Not that she was a bad sort really, old Mother Greenbank! Good old
		hospital—demobbed like everything else, I suppose?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence sighed.
		</p><p>
		“Yes. You too?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy nodded.
		</p><p>
		“Two months ago.”
		</p><p>
		“Gratuity?” hinted Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Spent.”
		</p><p>
		“Oh, Tommy!”
		</p><p>
		“No, old thing, not in riotous dissipation. No such luck! The cost of
		living—ordinary plain, or garden living nowadays is, I assure you, if you
		do not know——”
		</p><p>
		“My dear child,” interrupted Tuppence, “there is nothing I do
		not know about the cost of living. Here we are at Lyons’, and we
		will each of us pay for our own. That’s it!” And Tuppence led the
		way upstairs.
		</p><p>
		The place was full, and they wandered about looking for a table, catching odds
		and ends of conversation as they did so.
		</p><p>
		“And—do you know, she sat down and cried when I told her she
		couldn’t have the flat after all.” “It was simply a
		bargain, my dear! Just like the one Mabel Lewis brought from
		Paris——”
		</p><p>
		“Funny scraps one does overhear,” murmured Tommy. “I passed
		two Johnnies in the street to-day talking about some one called Jane Finn. Did
		you ever hear such a name?”
		</p><p>
		But at that moment two elderly ladies rose and collected parcels, and Tuppence
		deftly ensconced herself in one of the vacant seats.
		</p><p>
		Tommy ordered tea and buns. Tuppence ordered tea and buttered toast.
		</p><p>
		“And mind the tea comes in separate teapots,” she added severely.
		</p><p>
		Tommy sat down opposite her. His bared head revealed a shock of exquisitely
		slicked-back red hair. His face was pleasantly ugly—nondescript, yet
		unmistakably the face of a gentleman and a sportsman. His brown suit was well
		cut, but perilously near the end of its tether.
		</p><p>
		They were an essentially modern-looking couple as they sat there. Tuppence had
		no claim to beauty, but there was character and charm in the elfin lines of her
		little face, with its determined chin and large, wide-apart grey eyes that
		looked mistily out from under straight, black brows. She wore a small bright
		green toque over her black bobbed hair, and her extremely short and rather
		shabby skirt revealed a pair of uncommonly dainty ankles. Her appearance
		presented a valiant attempt at smartness.
		</p><p>
		The tea came at last, and Tuppence, rousing herself from a fit of meditation,
		poured it out.
		</p><p>
		“Now then,” said Tommy, taking a large bite of bun,
		“let’s get up-to-date. Remember, I haven’t seen you since
		that time in hospital in 1916.”
		</p><p>
		“Very well.” Tuppence helped herself liberally to buttered toast.
		“Abridged biography of Miss Prudence Cowley, fifth daughter of Archdeacon
		Cowley of Little Missendell, Suffolk. Miss Cowley left the delights (and
		drudgeries) of her home life early in the war and came up to London, where she
		entered an officers’ hospital. First month: Washed up six hundred and
		forty-eight plates every day. Second month: Promoted to drying aforesaid
		plates. Third month: Promoted to peeling potatoes. Fourth month: Promoted to
		cutting bread and butter. Fifth month: Promoted one floor up to duties of
		wardmaid with mop and pail. Sixth month: Promoted to waiting at table. Seventh
		month: Pleasing appearance and nice manners so striking that am promoted to
		waiting on the Sisters! Eighth month: Slight check in career. Sister Bond ate
		Sister Westhaven’s egg! Grand row! Wardmaid clearly to blame! Inattention
		in such important matters cannot be too highly censured. Mop and pail again!
		How are the mighty fallen! Ninth month: Promoted to sweeping out wards, where I
		found a friend of my childhood in Lieutenant Thomas Beresford (bow, Tommy!),
		whom I had not seen for five long years. The meeting was affecting! Tenth
		month: Reproved by matron for visiting the pictures in company with one of the
		patients, namely: the aforementioned Lieutenant Thomas Beresford. Eleventh and
		twelfth months: Parlourmaid duties resumed with entire success. At the end of
		the year left hospital in a blaze of glory. After that, the talented Miss
		Cowley drove successively a trade delivery van, a motor-lorry and a general!
		The last was the pleasantest. He was quite a young general!”
		</p><p>
		“What blighter was that?” inquired Tommy. “Perfectly
		sickening the way those brass hats drove from the War Office to the
		Savoy, and from the Savoy to the War Office!”
		</p><p>
		“I’ve forgotten his name now,” confessed Tuppence. “To
		resume, that was in a way the apex of my career. I next entered a Government
		office. We had several very enjoyable tea parties. I had intended to become a
		land girl, a postwoman, and a bus conductress by way of rounding off my
		career—but the Armistice intervened! I clung to the office with the true
		limpet touch for many long months, but, alas, I was combed out at last. Since
		then I’ve been looking for a job. Now then—your turn.”
		</p><p>
		“There’s not so much promotion in mine,” said Tommy
		regretfully, “and a great deal less variety. I went out to France again,
		as you know. Then they sent me to Mesopotamia, and I got wounded for the second
		time, and went into hospital out there. Then I got stuck in Egypt till the
		Armistice happened, kicked my heels there some time longer, and, as I told you,
		finally got demobbed. And, for ten long, weary months I’ve been job
		hunting! There aren’t any jobs! And, if there were, they wouldn’t
		give ‘em to me. What good am I? What do I know about business?
		Nothing.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence nodded gloomily.
		</p><p>
		“What about the colonies?” she suggested.
		</p><p>
		Tommy shook his head.
		</p><p>
		“I shouldn’t like the colonies—and I’m perfectly
		certain they wouldn’t like me!”
		</p><p>
		“Rich relations?”
		</p><p>
		Again Tommy shook his head.
		</p><p>
		“Oh, Tommy, not even a great-aunt?”
		</p><p>
		“I’ve got an old uncle who’s more or less rolling, but
		he’s no good.”
		</p><p>
		“Why not?”
		</p><p>
		“Wanted to adopt me once. I refused.”
		</p><p>
		“I think I remember hearing about it,” said Tuppence slowly.
		“You refused because of your mother——”
		</p><p>
		Tommy flushed.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, it would have been a bit rough on the mater. As you know, I was all
		she had. Old boy hated her—wanted to get me away from her. Just a bit of
		spite.”
		</p><p>
		“Your mother’s dead, isn’t she?” said Tuppence gently.
		</p><p>
		Tommy nodded.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence’s large grey eyes looked misty.
		</p><p>
		“You’re a good sort, Tommy. I always knew it.”
		</p><p>
		“Rot!” said Tommy hastily. “Well, that’s my position.
		I’m just about desperate.”
		</p><p>
		“So am I! I’ve hung out as long as I could. I’ve touted
		round. I’ve answered advertisements. I’ve tried every mortal
		blessed thing. I’ve screwed and saved and pinched! But it’s no
		good. I shall have to go home!”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t you want to?”
		</p><p>
		“Of course I don’t want to! What’s the good of being
		sentimental? Father’s a dear—I’m awfully fond of
		him—but you’ve no idea how I worry him! He has that delightful
		early Victorian view that short skirts and smoking are immoral. You can imagine
		what a thorn in the flesh I am to him! He just heaved a sigh of relief when the
		war took me off. You see, there are seven of us at home. It’s awful! All
		housework and mothers’ meetings! I have always been the changeling. I
		don’t want to go back, but—oh, Tommy, what else is there to
		do?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy shook his head sadly. There was a silence, and then Tuppence burst out:
		</p><p>
		“Money, money, money! I think about money morning, noon and night! I dare
		say it’s mercenary of me, but there it is!”
		</p><p>
		“Same here,” agreed Tommy with feeling.
		</p><p>
		“I’ve thought over every imaginable way of getting it too,”
		continued Tuppence. “There are only three! To be left it, to marry it, or
		to make it. First is ruled out. I haven’t got any rich elderly relatives.
		Any relatives I have are in homes for decayed gentlewomen! I always help old
		ladies over crossings, and pick up parcels for old gentlemen, in case they
		should turn out to be eccentric millionaires. But not one of them has ever
		asked me my name—and quite a lot never said ‘Thank
		you.’”
		</p><p>
		There was a pause.
		</p><p>
		“Of course,” resumed Tuppence, “marriage is my best chance. I
		made up my mind to marry money when I was quite young. Any thinking girl would!
		I’m not sentimental, you know.” She paused. “Come now, you
		can’t say I’m sentimental,” she added sharply.
		</p><p>
		“Certainly not,” agreed Tommy hastily. “No one would ever
		think of sentiment in connection with you.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s not very polite,” replied Tuppence. “But I dare
		say you mean it all right. Well, there it is! I’m ready and
		willing—but I never meet any rich men! All the boys I know are about as
		hard up as I am.”
		</p><p>
		“What about the general?” inquired Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“I fancy he keeps a bicycle shop in time of peace,” explained
		Tuppence. “No, there it is! Now you could marry a rich
		girl.”
		</p><p>
		“I’m like you. I don’t know any.”
		</p><p>
		“That doesn’t matter. You can always get to know one. Now, if I see
		a man in a fur coat come out of the Ritz I can’t rush up to him
		and say: ‘Look here, you’re rich. I’d like to know
		you.’”
		</p><p>
		“Do you suggest that I should do that to a similarly garbed
		female?”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t be silly. You tread on her foot, or pick up her
		handkerchief, or something like that. If she thinks you want to know her
		she’s flattered, and will manage it for you somehow.”
		</p><p>
		“You overrate my manly charms,” murmured Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“On the other hand,” proceeded Tuppence, “my millionaire
		would probably run for his life! No—marriage is fraught with
		difficulties. Remains—to make money!”
		</p><p>
		“We’ve tried that, and failed,” Tommy reminded her.
		</p><p>
		“We’ve tried all the orthodox ways, yes. But suppose we try the
		unorthodox. Tommy, let’s be adventurers!”
		</p><p>
		“Certainly,” replied Tommy cheerfully. “How do we
		begin?”
		</p><p>
		“That’s the difficulty. If we could make ourselves known, people
		might hire us to commit crimes for them.”
		</p><p>
		“Delightful,” commented Tommy. “Especially coming from a
		clergyman’s daughter!”
		</p><p>
		“The moral guilt,” Tuppence pointed out, “would be
		theirs—not mine. You must admit that there’s a difference between
		stealing a diamond necklace for yourself and being hired to steal it.”
		</p><p>
		“There wouldn’t be the least difference if you were caught!”
		</p><p>
		“Perhaps not. But I shouldn’t be caught. I’m so
		clever.”
		</p><p>
		“Modesty always was your besetting sin,” remarked Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“Don’t rag. Look here, Tommy, shall we really? Shall we form a
		business partnership?”
		</p><p>
		“Form a company for the stealing of diamond necklaces?”
		</p><p>
		“That was only an illustration. Let’s have a—what do you call
		it in book-keeping?”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t know. Never did any.”
		</p><p>
		“I have—but I always got mixed up, and used to put credit entries
		on the debit side, and vice versa—so they fired me out. Oh, I
		know—a joint venture! It struck me as such a romantic phrase to come
		across in the middle of musty old figures. It’s got an Elizabethan
		flavour about it—makes one think of galleons and doubloons. A joint
		venture!”
		</p><p>
		“Trading under the name of the Young Adventurers, Ltd.? Is that your
		idea, Tuppence?”
		</p><p>
		“It’s all very well to laugh, but I feel there might be something
		in it.”
		</p><p>
		“How do you propose to get in touch with your would-be employers?”
		</p><p>
		“Advertisement,” replied Tuppence promptly. “Have you got a
		bit of paper and a pencil? Men usually seem to have. Just like we have hairpins
		and powder-puffs.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy handed over a rather shabby green notebook, and Tuppence began writing
		busily.
		</p><p>
		“Shall we begin: ‘Young officer, twice wounded in the
		war——‘”
		</p><p>
		“Certainly not.”
		</p><p>
		“Oh, very well, my dear boy. But I can assure you that that sort of thing
		might touch the heart of an elderly spinster, and she might adopt you, and then
		there would be no need for you to be a young adventurer at all.”
		</p><p>
		“I don’t want to be adopted.”
		</p><p>
		“I forgot you had a prejudice against it. I was only ragging you! The
		papers are full up to the brim with that type of thing. Now
		listen—how’s this? ‘Two young adventurers for hire. Willing
		to do anything, go anywhere. Pay must be good.’ (We might as well make
		that clear from the start.) Then we might add: ‘No reasonable offer
		refused’—like flats and furniture.”
		</p><p>
		“I should think any offer we get in answer to that would be a pretty
		unreasonable one!”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy! You’re a genius! That’s ever so much more chic.
		‘No unreasonable offer refused—if pay is good.’ How’s
		that?”
		</p><p>
		“I shouldn’t mention pay again. It looks rather eager.”
		</p><p>
		“It couldn’t look as eager as I feel! But perhaps you are right.
		Now I’ll read it straight through. ‘Two young adventurers for hire.
		Willing to do anything, go anywhere. Pay must be good. No unreasonable offer
		refused.’ How would that strike you if you read it?”
		</p><p>
		“It would strike me as either being a hoax, or else written by a
		lunatic.”
		</p><p>
		“It’s not half so insane as a thing I read this morning beginning
		‘Petunia’ and signed ‘Best Boy.’” She tore out
		the leaf and handed it to Tommy. “There you are. Times, I think.
		Reply to Box so-and-so. I expect it will be about five shillings. Here’s
		half a crown for my share.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy was holding the paper thoughtfully. His faced burned a deeper red.
		</p><p>
		“Shall we really try it?” he said at last. “Shall we,
		Tuppence? Just for the fun of the thing?”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy, you’re a sport! I knew you would be! Let’s drink to
		success.” She poured some cold dregs of tea into the two cups.
		</p><p>
		“Here’s to our joint venture, and may it prosper!”
		</p><p>
		“The Young Adventurers, Ltd.!” responded Tommy.
		</p><p>
		They put down the cups and laughed rather uncertainly. Tuppence rose.
		</p><p>
		“I must return to my palatial suite at the hostel.”
		</p><p>
		“Perhaps it is time I strolled round to the Ritz,” agreed
		Tommy with a grin. “Where shall we meet? And when?”
		</p><p>
		“Twelve o’clock to-morrow. Piccadilly Tube station. Will that suit
		you?”
		</p><p>
		“My time is my own,” replied Mr. Beresford magnificently.
		</p><p>
		“So long, then.”
		</p><p>
		“Good-bye, old thing.”
		</p><p>
		The two young people went off in opposite directions. Tuppence’s hostel
		was situated in what was charitably called Southern Belgravia. For reasons of
		economy she did not take a bus.
		</p><p>
		She was half-way across St. James’s Park, when a man’s voice behind
		her made her start.
		</p><p>
		“Excuse me,” it said. “But may I speak to you for a
		moment?”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc3">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER II.
		MR. WHITTINGTON’S OFFER</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		Tuppence turned sharply, but the words hovering on the tip of her tongue
		remained unspoken, for the man’s appearance and manner did not bear out
		her first and most natural assumption. She hesitated. As if he read her
		thoughts, the man said quickly:
		</p><p>
		“I can assure you I mean no disrespect.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence believed him. Although she disliked and distrusted him instinctively,
		she was inclined to acquit him of the particular motive which she had at first
		attributed to him. She looked him up and down. He was a big man, clean shaven,
		with a heavy jowl. His eyes were small and cunning, and shifted their glance
		under her direct gaze.
		</p><p>
		“Well, what is it?” she asked.
		</p><p>
		The man smiled.
		</p><p>
		“I happened to overhear part of your conversation with the young
		gentleman in Lyons’.”
		</p><p>
		“Well—what of it?”
		</p><p>
		“Nothing—except that I think I may be of some use to you.”
		</p><p>
		Another inference forced itself into Tuppence’s mind:
		</p><p>
		“You followed me here?”
		</p><p>
		“I took that liberty.”
		</p><p>
		“And in what way do you think you could be of use to me?”
		</p><p>
		The man took a card from his pocket and handed it to her with a bow.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence took it and scrutinized it carefully. It bore the inscription,
		“Mr. Edward Whittington.” Below the name were the words
		“Esthonia Glassware Co.,” and the address of a city office. Mr.
		Whittington spoke again:
		</p><p>
		“If you will call upon me to-morrow morning at eleven o’clock, I
		will lay the details of my proposition before you.”
		</p><p>
		“At eleven o’clock?” said Tuppence doubtfully.
		</p><p>
		“At eleven o’clock.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence made up her mind.
		</p><p>
		“Very well. I’ll be there.”
		</p><p>
		“Thank you. Good evening.”
		</p><p>
		He raised his hat with a flourish, and walked away. Tuppence remained for some
		minutes gazing after him. Then she gave a curious movement of her shoulders,
		rather as a terrier shakes himself.
		</p><p>
		“The adventures have begun,” she murmured to herself. “What
		does he want me to do, I wonder? There’s something about you, Mr.
		Whittington, that I don’t like at all. But, on the other hand, I’m
		not the least bit afraid of you. And as I’ve said before, and shall
		doubtless say again, little Tuppence can look after herself, thank you!”
		</p><p>
		And with a short, sharp nod of her head she walked briskly onward. As a result
		of further meditations, however, she turned aside from the direct route and
		entered a post office. There she pondered for some moments, a telegraph form in
		her hand. The thought of a possible five shillings spent unnecessarily spurred
		her to action, and she decided to risk the waste of ninepence.
		</p><p>
		Disdaining the spiky pen and thick, black treacle which a beneficent Government
		had provided, Tuppence drew out Tommy’s pencil which she had retained and
		wrote rapidly: “Don’t put in advertisement. Will explain
		to-morrow.” She addressed it to Tommy at his club, from which in one
		short month he would have to resign, unless a kindly fortune permitted him to
		renew his subscription.
		</p><p>
		“It may catch him,” she murmured. “Anyway, it’s worth
		trying.”
		</p><p>
		After handing it over the counter she set out briskly for home, stopping at a
		baker’s to buy three penny-worth of new buns.
		</p><p>
		Later, in her tiny cubicle at the top of the house she munched buns and
		reflected on the future. What was the Esthonia Glassware Co., and what earthly
		need could it have for her services? A pleasurable thrill of excitement made
		Tuppence tingle. At any rate, the country vicarage had retreated into the
		background again. The morrow held possibilities.
		</p><p>
		It was a long time before Tuppence went to sleep that night, and, when at
		length she did, she dreamed that Mr. Whittington had set her to washing up a
		pile of Esthonia Glassware, which bore an unaccountable resemblance to hospital
		plates!
		</p><p>
		It wanted some five minutes to eleven when Tuppence reached the block of
		buildings in which the offices of the Esthonia Glassware Co. were situated. To
		arrive before the time would look over-eager. So Tuppence decided to walk to
		the end of the street and back again. She did so. On the stroke of eleven she
		plunged into the recesses of the building. The Esthonia Glassware Co. was on
		the top floor. There was a lift, but Tuppence chose to walk up.
		</p><p>
		Slightly out of breath, she came to a halt outside the ground glass door with
		the legend painted across it “Esthonia Glassware Co.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence knocked. In response to a voice from within, she turned the handle and
		walked into a small rather dirty outer office.
		</p><p>
		A middle-aged clerk got down from a high stool at a desk near the window and
		came towards her inquiringly.
		</p><p>
		“I have an appointment with Mr. Whittington,” said Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Will you come this way, please.” He crossed to a partition door
		with “Private” on it, knocked, then opened the door and stood aside
		to let her pass in.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Whittington was seated behind a large desk covered with papers. Tuppence
		felt her previous judgment confirmed. There was something wrong about Mr.
		Whittington. The combination of his sleek prosperity and his shifty eye was not
		attractive.
		</p><p>
		He looked up and nodded.
		</p><p>
		“So you’ve turned up all right? That’s good. Sit down, will
		you?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence sat down on the chair facing him. She looked particularly small and
		demure this morning. She sat there meekly with downcast eyes whilst Mr.
		Whittington sorted and rustled amongst his papers. Finally he pushed them away,
		and leaned over the desk.
		</p><p>
		“Now, my dear young lady, let us come to business.” His large face
		broadened into a smile. “You want work? Well, I have work to offer you.
		What should you say now to £100 down, and all expenses paid?” Mr.
		Whittington leaned back in his chair, and thrust his thumbs into the arm-holes
		of his waistcoat.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence eyed him warily.
		</p><p>
		“And the nature of the work?” she demanded.
		</p><p>
		“Nominal—purely nominal. A pleasant trip, that is all.”
		</p><p>
		“Where to?”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Whittington smiled again.
		</p><p>
		“Paris.”
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” said Tuppence thoughtfully. To herself she said: “Of
		course, if father heard that he would have a fit! But somehow I don’t see
		Mr. Whittington in the role of the gay deceiver.”
		</p><p>
		“Yes,” continued Whittington. “What could be more delightful?
		To put the clock back a few years—a very few, I am sure—and
		re-enter one of those charming pensionnats de jeunes filles with which
		Paris abounds——”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence interrupted him.
		</p><p>
		“A pensionnat?”
		</p><p>
		“Exactly. Madame Colombier’s in the Avenue de Neuilly.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence knew the name well. Nothing could have been more select. She had had
		several American friends there. She was more than ever puzzled.
		</p><p>
		“You want me to go to Madame Colombier’s? For how long?”
		</p><p>
		“That depends. Possibly three months.”
		</p><p>
		“And that is all? There are no other conditions?”
		</p><p>
		“None whatever. You would, of course, go in the character of my ward, and
		you would hold no communication with your friends. I should have to request
		absolute secrecy for the time being. By the way, you are English, are you
		not?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes.”
		</p><p>
		“Yet you speak with a slight American accent?”
		</p><p>
		“My great pal in hospital was a little American girl. I dare say I picked
		it up from her. I can soon get out of it again.”
		</p><p>
		“On the contrary, it might be simpler for you to pass as an American.
		Details about your past life in England might be more difficult to sustain.
		Yes, I think that would be decidedly better. Then——”
		</p><p>
		“One moment, Mr. Whittington! You seem to be taking my consent for
		granted.”
		</p><p>
		Whittington looked surprised.
		</p><p>
		“Surely you are not thinking of refusing? I can assure you that Madame
		Colombier’s is a most high-class and orthodox establishment. And the
		terms are most liberal.”
		</p><p>
		“Exactly,” said Tuppence. “That’s just it. The terms
		are almost too liberal, Mr. Whittington. I cannot see any way in which I can be
		worth that amount of money to you.”
		</p><p>
		“No?” said Whittington softly. “Well, I will tell you. I
		could doubtless obtain some one else for very much less. What I am willing to
		pay for is a young lady with sufficient intelligence and presence of mind to
		sustain her part well, and also one who will have sufficient discretion not to
		ask too many questions.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence smiled a little. She felt that Whittington had scored.
		</p><p>
		“There’s another thing. So far there has been no mention of Mr.
		Beresford. Where does he come in?”
		</p><p>
		“Mr. Beresford?”
		</p><p>
		“My partner,” said Tuppence with dignity. “You saw us
		together yesterday.”
		</p><p>
		“Ah, yes. But I’m afraid we shan’t require his
		services.”
		</p><p>
		“Then it’s off!” Tuppence rose. “It’s both or
		neither. Sorry—but that’s how it is. Good morning, Mr.
		Whittington.”
		</p><p>
		“Wait a minute. Let us see if something can’t be managed. Sit down
		again, Miss——” He paused interrogatively.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence’s conscience gave her a passing twinge as she remembered the
		archdeacon. She seized hurriedly on the first name that came into her head.
		</p><p>
		“Jane Finn,” she said hastily; and then paused open-mouthed at the
		effect of those two simple words.
		</p><p>
		All the geniality had faded out of Whittington’s face. It was purple with
		rage, and the veins stood out on the forehead. And behind it all there lurked a
		sort of incredulous dismay. He leaned forward and hissed savagely:
		</p><p>
		“So that’s your little game, is it?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence, though utterly taken aback, nevertheless kept her head. She had not
		the faintest comprehension of his meaning, but she was naturally quick-witted,
		and felt it imperative to “keep her end up” as she phrased it.
		</p><p>
		Whittington went on:
		</p><p>
		“Been playing with me, have you, all the time, like a cat and mouse? Knew
		all the time what I wanted you for, but kept up the comedy. Is that it,
		eh?” He was cooling down. The red colour was ebbing out of his face. He
		eyed her keenly. “Who’s been blabbing? Rita?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence shook her head. She was doubtful as to how long she could sustain this
		illusion, but she realized the importance of not dragging an unknown Rita into
		it.
		</p><p>
		“No,” she replied with perfect truth. “Rita knows nothing
		about me.”
		</p><p>
		His eyes still bored into her like gimlets.
		</p><p>
		“How much do you know?” he shot out.
		</p><p>
		“Very little indeed,” answered Tuppence, and was pleased to note
		that Whittington’s uneasiness was augmented instead of allayed. To have
		boasted that she knew a lot might have raised doubts in his mind.
		</p><p>
		“Anyway,” snarled Whittington, “you knew enough to come in
		here and plump out that name.”
		</p><p>
		“It might be my own name,” Tuppence pointed out.
		</p><p>
		“It’s likely, isn’t it, then there would be two girls with a
		name like that?”
		</p><p>
		“Or I might just have hit upon it by chance,” continued Tuppence,
		intoxicated with the success of truthfulness.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Whittington brought his fist down upon the desk with a bang.
		</p><p>
		“Quit fooling! How much do you know? And how much do you want?”
		</p><p>
		The last five words took Tuppence’s fancy mightily, especially after a
		meagre breakfast and a supper of buns the night before. Her present part was of
		the adventuress rather than the adventurous order, but she did not deny its
		possibilities. She sat up and smiled with the air of one who has the situation
		thoroughly well in hand.
		</p><p>
		“My dear Mr. Whittington,” she said, “let us by all means lay
		our cards upon the table. And pray do not be so angry. You heard me say
		yesterday that I proposed to live by my wits. It seems to me that I have now
		proved I have some wits to live by! I admit I have knowledge of a certain name,
		but perhaps my knowledge ends there.”
		</p><p>
		“Yes—and perhaps it doesn’t,” snarled Whittington.
		</p><p>
		“You insist on misjudging me,” said Tuppence, and sighed gently.
		</p><p>
		“As I said once before,” said Whittington angrily, “quit
		fooling, and come to the point. You can’t play the innocent with me. You
		know a great deal more than you’re willing to admit.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence paused a moment to admire her own ingenuity, and then said softly:
		</p><p>
		“I shouldn’t like to contradict you, Mr. Whittington.”
		</p><p>
		“So we come to the usual question—how much?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence was in a dilemma. So far she had fooled Whittington with complete
		success, but to mention a palpably impossible sum might awaken his suspicions.
		An idea flashed across her brain.
		</p><p>
		“Suppose we say a little something down, and a fuller discussion of the
		matter later?”
		</p><p>
		Whittington gave her an ugly glance.
		</p><p>
		“Blackmail, eh?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence smiled sweetly.
		</p><p>
		“Oh no! Shall we say payment of services in advance?”
		</p><p>
		Whittington grunted.
		</p><p>
		“You see,” explained Tuppence still sweetly, “I’m so
		very fond of money!”
		</p><p>
		“You’re about the limit, that’s what you are,” growled
		Whittington, with a sort of unwilling admiration. “You took me in all
		right. Thought you were quite a meek little kid with just enough brains for my
		purpose.”
		</p><p>
		“Life,” moralized Tuppence, “is full of surprises.”
		</p><p>
		“All the same,” continued Whittington, “some one’s been
		talking. You say it isn’t Rita. Was it——? Oh, come in.”
		</p><p>
		The clerk followed his discreet knock into the room, and laid a paper at his
		master’s elbow.
		</p><p>
		“Telephone message just come for you, sir.”
		</p><p>
		Whittington snatched it up and read it. A frown gathered on his brow.
		</p><p>
		“That’ll do, Brown. You can go.”
		</p><p>
		The clerk withdrew, closing the door behind him. Whittington turned to
		Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Come to-morrow at the same time. I’m busy now. Here’s fifty
		to go on with.”
		</p><p>
		He rapidly sorted out some notes, and pushed them across the table to Tuppence,
		then stood up, obviously impatient for her to go.
		</p><p>
		The girl counted the notes in a businesslike manner, secured them in her
		handbag, and rose.
		</p><p>
		“Good morning, Mr. Whittington,” she said politely. “At
		least, au revoir, I should say.”
		</p><p>
		“Exactly. Au revoir!” Whittington looked almost genial again, a
		reversion that aroused in Tuppence a faint misgiving. “Au revoir, my
		clever and charming young lady.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence sped lightly down the stairs. A wild elation possessed her. A
		neighbouring clock showed the time to be five minutes to twelve.
		</p><p>
		“Let’s give Tommy a surprise!” murmured Tuppence, and hailed
		a taxi.
		</p><p>
		The cab drew up outside the tube station. Tommy was just within the entrance.
		His eyes opened to their fullest extent as he hurried forward to assist
		Tuppence to alight. She smiled at him affectionately, and remarked in a
		slightly affected voice:
		</p><p>
		“Pay the thing, will you, old bean? I’ve got nothing smaller than a
		five-pound note!”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc4">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER III.
		A SET BACK</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		The moment was not quite so triumphant as it ought to have been. To begin with,
		the resources of Tommy’s pockets were somewhat limited. In the end the
		fare was managed, the lady recollecting a plebeian twopence, and the driver,
		still holding the varied assortment of coins in his hand, was prevailed upon to
		move on, which he did after one last hoarse demand as to what the gentleman
		thought he was giving him?
		</p><p>
		“I think you’ve given him too much, Tommy,” said Tuppence
		innocently. “I fancy he wants to give some of it back.”
		</p><p>
		It was possibly this remark which induced the driver to move away.
		</p><p>
		“Well,” said Mr. Beresford, at length able to relieve his feelings,
		“what the—dickens, did you want to take a taxi for?”
		</p><p>
		“I was afraid I might be late and keep you waiting,” said Tuppence
		gently.
		</p><p>
		“Afraid—you—might—be—late! Oh, Lord, I give it
		up!” said Mr. Beresford.
		</p><p>
		“And really and truly,” continued Tuppence, opening her eyes very
		wide, “I haven’t got anything smaller than a five-pound
		note.”
		</p><p>
		“You did that part of it very well, old bean, but all the same the fellow
		wasn’t taken in—not for a moment!”
		</p><p>
		“No,” said Tuppence thoughtfully, “he didn’t believe
		it. That’s the curious part about speaking the truth. No one does believe
		it. I found that out this morning. Now let’s go to lunch. How about the
		Savoy?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy grinned.
		</p><p>
		“How about the Ritz?”
		</p><p>
		“On second thoughts, I prefer the Piccadilly. It’s nearer.
		We shan’t have to take another taxi. Come along.”
		</p><p>
		“Is this a new brand of humour? Or is your brain really unhinged?”
		inquired Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“Your last supposition is the correct one. I have come into money, and
		the shock has been too much for me! For that particular form of mental trouble
		an eminent physician recommends unlimited Hors d’œuvre,
		Lobster à l’américane, Chicken Newberg, and Pêche Melba!
		Let’s go and get them!”
		</p><p>
		“Tuppence, old girl, what has really come over you?”
		</p><p>
		“Oh, unbelieving one!” Tuppence wrenched open her bag. “Look
		here, and here, and here!”
		</p><p>
		“Great Jehosaphat! My dear girl, don’t wave Fishers aloft like
		that!”
		</p><p>
		“They’re not Fishers. They’re five times better than Fishers,
		and this one’s ten times better!”
		</p><p>
		Tommy groaned.
		</p><p>
		“I must have been drinking unawares! Am I dreaming, Tuppence, or do I
		really behold a large quantity of five-pound notes being waved about in a
		dangerous fashion?”
		</p><p>
		“Even so, O King! Now, will you come and have lunch?”
		</p><p>
		“I’ll come anywhere. But what have you been doing? Holding up a
		bank?”
		</p><p>
		“All in good time. What an awful place Piccadilly Circus is.
		There’s a huge bus bearing down on us. It would be too terrible if they
		killed the five-pound notes!”
		</p><p>
		“Grill room?” inquired Tommy, as they reached the opposite pavement
		in safety.
		</p><p>
		“The other’s more expensive,” demurred Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“That’s mere wicked wanton extravagance. Come on below.”
		</p><p>
		“Are you sure I can get all the things I want there?”
		</p><p>
		“That extremely unwholesome menu you were outlining just now? Of course
		you can—or as much as is good for you, anyway.”
		</p><p>
		“And now tell me,” said Tommy, unable to restrain his pent-up
		curiosity any longer, as they sat in state surrounded by the many hors
		d’œuvre of Tuppence’s dreams.
		</p><p>
		Miss Cowley told him.
		</p><p>
		“And the curious part of it is,” she ended, “that I really
		did invent the name of Jane Finn! I didn’t want to give my own because of
		poor father—in case I should get mixed up in anything shady.”
		</p><p>
		“Perhaps that’s so,” said Tommy slowly. “But you
		didn’t invent it.”
		</p><p>
		“What?”
		</p><p>
		“No. I told it to you. Don’t you remember, I said yesterday
		I’d overheard two people talking about a female called Jane Finn?
		That’s what brought the name into your mind so pat.”
		</p><p>
		“So you did. I remember now. How extraordinary——”
		Tuppence tailed off into silence. Suddenly she aroused herself.
		“Tommy!”
		</p><p>
		“Yes?”
		</p><p>
		“What were they like, the two men you passed?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy frowned in an effort at remembrance.
		</p><p>
		“One was a big fat sort of chap. Clean shaven, I think—and
		dark.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s him,” cried Tuppence, in an ungrammatical squeal.
		“That’s Whittington! What was the other man like?”
		</p><p>
		“I can’t remember. I didn’t notice him particularly. It was
		really the outlandish name that caught my attention.”
		</p><p>
		“And people say that coincidences don’t happen!” Tuppence
		tackled her Pêche Melba happily.
		</p><p>
		But Tommy had become serious.
		</p><p>
		“Look here, Tuppence, old girl, what is this going to lead to?”
		</p><p>
		“More money,” replied his companion.
		</p><p>
		“I know that. You’ve only got one idea in your head. What I mean
		is, what about the next step? How are you going to keep the game up?”
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” Tuppence laid down her spoon. “You’re right,
		Tommy, it is a bit of a poser.”
		</p><p>
		“After all, you know, you can’t bluff him forever. You’re
		sure to slip up sooner or later. And, anyway, I’m not at all sure that it
		isn’t actionable—blackmail, you know.”
		</p><p>
		“Nonsense. Blackmail is saying you’ll tell unless you are given
		money. Now, there’s nothing I could tell, because I don’t really
		know anything.”
		</p><p>
		“Hm,” said Tommy doubtfully. “Well, anyway, what are
		we going to do? Whittington was in a hurry to get rid of you this morning, but
		next time he’ll want to know something more before he parts with his
		money. He’ll want to know how much you know, and where you got
		your information from, and a lot of other things that you can’t cope
		with. What are you going to do about it?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence frowned severely.
		</p><p>
		“We must think. Order some Turkish coffee, Tommy. Stimulating to the
		brain. Oh, dear, what a lot I have eaten!”
		</p><p>
		“You have made rather a hog of yourself! So have I for that matter, but I
		flatter myself that my choice of dishes was more judicious than yours. Two
		coffees.” (This was to the waiter.) “One Turkish, one
		French.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence sipped her coffee with a deeply reflective air, and snubbed Tommy when
		he spoke to her.
		</p><p>
		“Be quiet. I’m thinking.”
		</p><p>
		“Shades of Pelmanism!” said Tommy, and relapsed into silence.
		</p><p>
		“There!” said Tuppence at last. “I’ve got a plan.
		Obviously what we’ve got to do is to find out more about it all.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy applauded.
		</p><p>
		“Don’t jeer. We can only find out through Whittington. We must
		discover where he lives, what he does—sleuth him, in fact! Now I
		can’t do it, because he knows me, but he only saw you for a minute or two
		in Lyons’. He’s not likely to recognize you. After all, one young
		man is much like another.”
		</p><p>
		“I repudiate that remark utterly. I’m sure my pleasing features and
		distinguished appearance would single me out from any crowd.”
		</p><p>
		“My plan is this,” Tuppence went on calmly, “I’ll go
		alone to-morrow. I’ll put him off again like I did to-day. It
		doesn’t matter if I don’t get any more money at once. Fifty pounds
		ought to last us a few days.”
		</p><p>
		“Or even longer!”
		</p><p>
		“You’ll hang about outside. When I come out I shan’t speak to
		you in case he’s watching. But I’ll take up my stand somewhere
		near, and when he comes out of the building I’ll drop a handkerchief or
		something, and off you go!”
		</p><p>
		“Off I go where?”
		</p><p>
		“Follow him, of course, silly! What do you think of the idea?”
		</p><p>
		“Sort of thing one reads about in books. I somehow feel that in real life
		one will feel a bit of an ass standing in the street for hours with nothing to
		do. People will wonder what I’m up to.”
		</p><p>
		“Not in the city. Every one’s in such a hurry. Probably no one will
		even notice you at all.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s the second time you’ve made that sort of remark.
		Never mind, I forgive you. Anyway, it will be rather a lark. What are you doing
		this afternoon?”
		</p><p>
		“Well,” said Tuppence meditatively. “I had thought of
		hats! Or perhaps silk stockings! Or perhaps——”
		</p><p>
		“Hold hard,” admonished Tommy. “There’s a limit to
		fifty pounds! But let’s do dinner and a show to-night at all
		events.”
		</p><p>
		“Rather.”
		</p><p>
		The day passed pleasantly. The evening even more so. Two of the five-pound
		notes were now irretrievably dead.
		</p><p>
		They met by arrangement the following morning and proceeded citywards. Tommy
		remained on the opposite side of the road while Tuppence plunged into the
		building.
		</p><p>
		Tommy strolled slowly down to the end of the street, then back again. Just as
		he came abreast of the building, Tuppence darted across the road.
		</p><p>
		“Tommy!”
		</p><p>
		“Yes. What’s up?”
		</p><p>
		“The place is shut. I can’t make anyone hear.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s odd.”
		</p><p>
		“Isn’t it? Come up with me, and let’s try again.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy followed her. As they passed the third floor landing a young clerk came
		out of an office. He hesitated a moment, then addressed himself to Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Were you wanting the Esthonia Glassware?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, please.”
		</p><p>
		“It’s closed down. Since yesterday afternoon. Company being wound
		up, they say. Not that I’ve ever heard of it myself. But anyway the
		office is to let.”
		</p><p>
		“Th—thank you,” faltered Tuppence. “I suppose you
		don’t know Mr. Whittington’s address?”
		</p><p>
		“Afraid I don’t. They left rather suddenly.”
		</p><p>
		“Thank you very much,” said Tommy. “Come on, Tuppence.”
		</p><p>
		They descended to the street again where they gazed at one another blankly.
		</p><p>
		“That’s torn it,” said Tommy at length.
		</p><p>
		“And I never suspected it,” wailed Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Cheer up, old thing, it can’t be helped.”
		</p><p>
		“Can’t it, though!” Tuppence’s little chin shot out
		defiantly. “Do you think this is the end? If so, you’re wrong.
		It’s just the beginning!”
		</p><p>
		“The beginning of what?”
		</p><p>
		“Of our adventure! Tommy, don’t you see, if they are scared enough
		to run away like this, it shows that there must be a lot in this Jane Finn
		business! Well, we’ll get to the bottom of it. We’ll run them down!
		We’ll be sleuths in earnest!”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, but there’s no one left to sleuth.”
		</p><p>
		“No, that’s why we’ll have to start all over again. Lend me
		that bit of pencil. Thanks. Wait a minute—don’t interrupt.
		There!” Tuppence handed back the pencil, and surveyed the piece of paper
		on which she had written with a satisfied eye:
		</p><p>
		“What’s that?”
		</p><p>
		“Advertisement.”
		</p><p>
		“You’re not going to put that thing in after all?”
		</p><p>
		“No, it’s a different one.” She handed him the slip of paper.
		</p><p>
		Tommy read the words on it aloud:
		</p><p>
		“WANTED, any information respecting Jane Finn. Apply Y. A.”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc5">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER IV.
		WHO IS JANE FINN?</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		The next day passed slowly. It was necessary to curtail expenditure. Carefully
		husbanded, forty pounds will last a long time. Luckily the weather was fine,
		and “walking is cheap,” dictated Tuppence. An outlying picture
		house provided them with recreation for the evening.
		</p><p>
		The day of disillusionment had been a Wednesday. On Thursday the advertisement
		had duly appeared. On Friday letters might be expected to arrive at
		Tommy’s rooms.
		</p><p>
		He had been bound by an honourable promise not to open any such letters if they
		did arrive, but to repair to the National Gallery, where his colleague would
		meet him at ten o’clock.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence was first at the rendezvous. She ensconced herself on a red velvet
		seat, and gazed at the Turners with unseeing eyes until she saw the familiar
		figure enter the room.
		</p><p>
		“Well?”
		</p><p>
		“Well,” returned Mr. Beresford provokingly. “Which is your
		favourite picture?”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t be a wretch. Aren’t there any answers?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy shook his head with a deep and somewhat overacted melancholy.
		</p><p>
		“I didn’t want to disappoint you, old thing, by telling you right
		off. It’s too bad. Good money wasted.” He sighed. “Still,
		there it is. The advertisement has appeared, and—there are only two
		answers!”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy, you devil!” almost screamed Tuppence. “Give them to
		me. How could you be so mean!”
		</p><p>
		“Your language, Tuppence, your language! They’re very particular at
		the National Gallery. Government show, you know. And do remember, as I have
		pointed out to you before, that as a clergyman’s
		daughter——”
		</p><p>
		“I ought to be on the stage!” finished Tuppence with a snap.
		</p><p>
		“That is not what I intended to say. But if you are sure that you have
		enjoyed to the full the reaction of joy after despair with which I have kindly
		provided you free of charge, let us get down to our mail, as the saying
		goes.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence snatched the two precious envelopes from him unceremoniously, and
		scrutinized them carefully.
		</p><p>
		“Thick paper, this one. It looks rich. We’ll keep it to the last
		and open the other first.”
		</p><p>
		“Right you are. One, two, three, go!”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence’s little thumb ripped open the envelope, and she extracted the
		contents.
		</p><p>
		“DEAR SIR,
		</p><p>
		“Referring to your advertisement in this morning’s paper, I may be
		able to be of some use to you. Perhaps you could call and see me at the above
		address at eleven o’clock to-morrow morning.
		</p><p>
		“Yours truly,
		</p><p>
		“A. CARTER.”
		</p><p>
		“27 Carshalton Gardens,” said Tuppence, referring to the address.
		“That’s Gloucester Road way. Plenty of time to get there if we
		tube.”
		</p><p>
		“The following,” said Tommy, “is the plan of campaign. It is
		my turn to assume the offensive. Ushered into the presence of Mr. Carter, he
		and I wish each other good morning as is customary. He then says: ‘Please
		take a seat, Mr.—er?’ To which I reply promptly and significantly:
		‘Edward Whittington!’ whereupon Mr. Carter turns purple in the face
		and gasps out: ‘How much?’ Pocketing the usual fee of fifty pounds,
		I rejoin you in the road outside, and we proceed to the next address and repeat
		the performance.”
		</p><p>
		“Don’t be absurd, Tommy. Now for the other letter. Oh, this is from
		the Ritz!”
		</p><p>
		“A hundred pounds instead of fifty!”
		</p><p>
		“I’ll read it:
		</p><p>
		“DEAR SIR,
		</p><p>
		“Re your advertisement, I should be glad if you would call round
		somewhere about lunch-time.
		</p><p>
		“Yours truly,
		</p><p>
		“JULIUS P. HERSHEIMMER.”
		</p><p>
		“Ha!” said Tommy. “Do I smell a Boche? Or only an American
		millionaire of unfortunate ancestry? At all events we’ll call at
		lunch-time. It’s a good time—frequently leads to free food for
		two.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence nodded assent.
		</p><p>
		“Now for Carter. We’ll have to hurry.”
		</p><p>
		Carshalton Terrace proved to be an unimpeachable row of what Tuppence called
		“ladylike looking houses.” They rang the bell at No. 27, and a neat
		maid answered the door. She looked so respectable that Tuppence’s heart
		sank. Upon Tommy’s request for Mr. Carter, she showed them into a small
		study on the ground floor where she left them. Hardly a minute elapsed,
		however, before the door opened, and a tall man with a lean hawklike face and a
		tired manner entered the room.
		</p><p>
		“Mr. Y. A.?” he said, and smiled. His smile was distinctly
		attractive. “Do sit down, both of you.”
		</p><p>
		They obeyed. He himself took a chair opposite to Tuppence and smiled at her
		encouragingly. There was something in the quality of his smile that made the
		girl’s usual readiness desert her.
		</p><p>
		As he did not seem inclined to open the conversation, Tuppence was forced to
		begin.
		</p><p>
		“We wanted to know—that is, would you be so kind as to tell us
		anything you know about Jane Finn?”
		</p><p>
		“Jane Finn? Ah!” Mr. Carter appeared to reflect. “Well, the
		question is, what do you know about her?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence drew herself up.
		</p><p>
		“I don’t see that that’s got anything to do with it.”
		</p><p>
		“No? But it has, you know, really it has.” He smiled again in his
		tired way, and continued reflectively. “So that brings us down to it
		again. What do you know about Jane Finn?
		</p><p>
		“Come now,” he continued, as Tuppence remained silent. “You
		must know something to have advertised as you did?” He leaned
		forward a little, his weary voice held a hint of persuasiveness. “Suppose
		you tell me....”
		</p><p>
		There was something very magnetic about Mr. Carter’s personality.
		Tuppence seemed to shake herself free of it with an effort, as she said:
		</p><p>
		“We couldn’t do that, could we, Tommy?”
		</p><p>
		But to her surprise, her companion did not back her up. His eyes were fixed on
		Mr. Carter, and his tone when he spoke held an unusual note of deference.
		</p><p>
		“I dare say the little we know won’t be any good to you, sir. But
		such as it is, you’re welcome to it.”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy!” cried out Tuppence in surprise.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter slewed round in his chair. His eyes asked a question.
		</p><p>
		Tommy nodded.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, sir, I recognized you at once. Saw you in France when I was with
		the Intelligence. As soon as you came into the room, I
		knew——”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter held up his hand.
		</p><p>
		“No names, please. I’m known as Mr. Carter here. It’s my
		cousin’s house, by the way. She’s willing to lend it to me
		sometimes when it’s a case of working on strictly unofficial lines. Well,
		now”—he looked from one to the other—“who’s going
		to tell me the story?”
		</p><p>
		“Fire ahead, Tuppence,” directed Tommy. “It’s your
		yarn.”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, little lady, out with it.”
		</p><p>
		And obediently Tuppence did out with it, telling the whole story from the
		forming of the Young Adventurers, Ltd., downwards.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter listened in silence with a resumption of his tired manner. Now and
		then he passed his hand across his lips as though to hide a smile. When she had
		finished he nodded gravely.
		</p><p>
		“Not much. But suggestive. Quite suggestive. If you’ll excuse my
		saying so, you’re a curious young couple. I don’t know—you
		might succeed where others have failed ... I believe in luck, you
		know—always have....”
		</p><p>
		He paused a moment, and then went on.
		</p><p>
		“Well, how about it? You’re out for adventure. How would you like
		to work for me? All quite unofficial, you know. Expenses paid, and a moderate
		screw?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence gazed at him, her lips parted, her eyes growing wider and wider.
		</p><p>
		“What should we have to do?” she breathed.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter smiled.
		</p><p>
		“Just go on with what you’re doing now. Find Jane
		Finn.”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, but—who is Jane Finn?”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter nodded gravely.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, you’re entitled to know that, I think.”
		</p><p>
		He leaned back in his chair, crossed his legs, brought the tips of his fingers
		together, and began in a low monotone:
		</p><p>
		“Secret diplomacy (which, by the way, is nearly always bad policy!) does
		not concern you. It will be sufficient to say that in the early days of 1915 a
		certain document came into being. It was the draft of a secret
		agreement—treaty—call it what you like. It was drawn up ready for
		signature by the various representatives, and drawn up in America—at that
		time a neutral country. It was dispatched to England by a special messenger
		selected for that purpose, a young fellow called Danvers. It was hoped that the
		whole affair had been kept so secret that nothing would have leaked out. That
		kind of hope is usually disappointed. Somebody always talks!
		</p><p>
		“Danvers sailed for England on the Lusitania. He carried the
		precious papers in an oilskin packet which he wore next his skin. It was on
		that particular voyage that the Lusitania was torpedoed and sunk.
		Danvers was among the list of those missing. Eventually his body was washed
		ashore, and identified beyond any possible doubt. But the oilskin packet was
		missing!
		</p><p>
		“The question was, had it been taken from him, or had he himself passed
		it on into another’s keeping? There were a few incidents that
		strengthened the possibility of the latter theory. After the torpedo struck the
		ship, in the few moments during the launching of the boats, Danvers was seen
		speaking to a young American girl. No one actually saw him pass anything to
		her, but he might have done so. It seems to me quite likely that he entrusted
		the papers to this girl, believing that she, as a woman, had a greater chance
		of bringing them safely to shore.
		</p><p>
		“But if so, where was the girl, and what had she done with the papers? By
		later advice from America it seemed likely that Danvers had been closely
		shadowed on the way over. Was this girl in league with his enemies? Or had she,
		in her turn, been shadowed and either tricked or forced into handing over the
		precious packet?
		</p><p>
		“We set to work to trace her out. It proved unexpectedly difficult. Her
		name was Jane Finn, and it duly appeared among the list of the survivors, but
		the girl herself seemed to have vanished completely. Inquiries into her
		antecedents did little to help us. She was an orphan, and had been what we
		should call over here a pupil teacher in a small school out West. Her passport
		had been made out for Paris, where she was going to join the staff of a
		hospital. She had offered her services voluntarily, and after some
		correspondence they had been accepted. Having seen her name in the list of the
		saved from the Lusitania, the staff of the hospital were naturally very
		surprised at her not arriving to take up her billet, and at not hearing from
		her in any way.
		</p><p>
		“Well, every effort was made to trace the young lady—but all in
		vain. We tracked her across Ireland, but nothing could be heard of her after
		she set foot in England. No use was made of the draft treaty—as might
		very easily have been done—and we therefore came to the conclusion that
		Danvers had, after all, destroyed it. The war entered on another phase, the
		diplomatic aspect changed accordingly, and the treaty was never redrafted.
		Rumours as to its existence were emphatically denied. The disappearance of Jane
		Finn was forgotten and the whole affair was lost in oblivion.”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter paused, and Tuppence broke in impatiently:
		</p><p>
		“But why has it all cropped up again? The war’s over.”
		</p><p>
		A hint of alertness came into Mr. Carter’s manner.
		</p><p>
		“Because it seems that the papers were not destroyed after all, and that
		they might be resurrected to-day with a new and deadly significance.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence stared. Mr. Carter nodded.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, five years ago, that draft treaty was a weapon in our hands; to-day
		it is a weapon against us. It was a gigantic blunder. If its terms were made
		public, it would mean disaster.... It might possibly bring about another
		war—not with Germany this time! That is an extreme possibility, and I do
		not believe in its likelihood myself, but that document undoubtedly implicates
		a number of our statesmen whom we cannot afford to have discredited in any way
		at the present moment. As a party cry for Labour it would be irresistible, and
		a Labour Government at this juncture would, in my opinion, be a grave
		disability for British trade, but that is a mere nothing to the real
		danger.”
		</p><p>
		He paused, and then said quietly:
		</p><p>
		“You may perhaps have heard or read that there is Bolshevist influence at
		work behind the present Labour unrest?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence nodded.
		</p><p>
		“That is the truth. Bolshevist gold is pouring into this country for the
		specific purpose of procuring a Revolution. And there is a certain man, a man
		whose real name is unknown to us, who is working in the dark for his own ends.
		The Bolshevists are behind the Labour unrest—but this man is behind
		the Bolshevists. Who is he? We do not know. He is always spoken of by the
		unassuming title of ‘Mr. Brown.’ But one thing is certain, he is
		the master criminal of this age. He controls a marvellous organization. Most of
		the Peace propaganda during the war was originated and financed by him. His
		spies are everywhere.”
		</p><p>
		“A naturalized German?” asked Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“On the contrary, I have every reason to believe he is an Englishman. He
		was pro-German, as he would have been pro-Boer. What he seeks to attain we do
		not know—probably supreme power for himself, of a kind unique in history.
		We have no clue as to his real personality. It is reported that even his own
		followers are ignorant of it. Where we have come across his tracks, he has
		always played a secondary part. Somebody else assumes the chief rôle. But
		afterwards we always find that there has been some nonentity, a servant or a
		clerk, who has remained in the background unnoticed, and that the elusive Mr.
		Brown has escaped us once more.”
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” Tuppence jumped. “I wonder——”
		</p><p>
		“Yes?”
		</p><p>
		“I remember in Mr. Whittington’s office. The clerk—he called
		him Brown. You don’t think——”
		</p><p>
		Carter nodded thoughtfully.
		</p><p>
		“Very likely. A curious point is that the name is usually mentioned. An
		idiosyncrasy of genius. Can you describe him at all?”
		</p><p>
		“I really didn’t notice. He was quite ordinary—just like
		anyone else.”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter sighed in his tired manner.
		</p><p>
		“That is the invariable description of Mr. Brown! Brought a telephone
		message to the man Whittington, did he? Notice a telephone in the outer
		office?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence thought.
		</p><p>
		“No, I don’t think I did.”
		</p><p>
		“Exactly. That ‘message’ was Mr. Brown’s way of giving
		an order to his subordinate. He overheard the whole conversation of course. Was
		it after that that Whittington handed you over the money, and told you to come
		the following day?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence nodded.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, undoubtedly the hand of Mr. Brown!” Mr. Carter paused.
		“Well, there it is, you see what you are pitting yourselves against?
		Possibly the finest criminal brain of the age. I don’t quite like it, you
		know. You’re such young things, both of you. I shouldn’t like
		anything to happen to you.”
		</p><p>
		“It won’t,” Tuppence assured him positively.
		</p><p>
		“I’ll look after her, sir,” said Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“And I’ll look after you,” retorted Tuppence,
		resenting the manly assertion.
		</p><p>
		“Well, then, look after each other,” said Mr. Carter, smiling.
		“Now let’s get back to business. There’s something mysterious
		about this draft treaty that we haven’t fathomed yet. We’ve been
		threatened with it—in plain and unmistakable terms. The Revolutionary
		element as good as declare that it’s in their hands, and that they intend
		to produce it at a given moment. On the other hand, they are clearly at fault
		about many of its provisions. The Government consider it as mere bluff on their
		part, and, rightly or wrongly, have stuck to the policy of absolute denial.
		I’m not so sure. There have been hints, indiscreet allusions, that seem
		to indicate that the menace is a real one. The position is much as though they
		had got hold of an incriminating document, but couldn’t read it because
		it was in cipher—but we know that the draft treaty wasn’t in
		cipher—couldn’t be in the nature of things—so that
		won’t wash. But there’s something. Of course, Jane Finn may
		be dead for all we know—but I don’t think so. The curious thing is
		that they’re trying to get information about the girl from
		us.”
		</p><p>
		“What?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes. One or two little things have cropped up. And your story, little
		lady, confirms my idea. They know we’re looking for Jane Finn. Well,
		they’ll produce a Jane Finn of their own—say at a pensionnat
		in Paris.” Tuppence gasped, and Mr. Carter smiled. “No one knows in
		the least what she looks like, so that’s all right. She’s primed
		with a trumped-up tale, and her real business is to get as much information as
		possible out of us. See the idea?”
		</p><p>
		“Then you think”—Tuppence paused to grasp the supposition
		fully—“that it was as Jane Finn that they wanted me to go to
		Paris?”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter smiled more wearily than ever.
		</p><p>
		“I believe in coincidences, you know,” he said.

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc6">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER V.
		MR. JULIUS P. HERSHEIMMER</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		“Well,” said Tuppence, recovering herself, “it really seems
		as though it were meant to be.”
		</p><p>
		Carter nodded.
		</p><p>
		“I know what you mean. I’m superstitious myself. Luck, and all that
		sort of thing. Fate seems to have chosen you out to be mixed up in this.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy indulged in a chuckle.
		</p><p>
		“My word! I don’t wonder Whittington got the wind up when Tuppence
		plumped out that name! I should have myself. But look here, sir, we’re
		taking up an awful lot of your time. Have you any tips to give us before we
		clear out?”
		</p><p>
		“I think not. My experts, working in stereotyped ways, have failed. You
		will bring imagination and an open mind to the task. Don’t be discouraged
		if that too does not succeed. For one thing there is a likelihood of the pace
		being forced.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence frowned uncomprehendingly.
		</p><p>
		“When you had that interview with Whittington, they had time before them.
		I have information that the big coup was planned for early in the new
		year. But the Government is contemplating legislative action which will deal
		effectually with the strike menace. They’ll get wind of it soon, if they
		haven’t already, and it’s possible that that may bring things to a
		head. I hope it will myself. The less time they have to mature their plans the
		better. I’m just warning you that you haven’t much time before you,
		and that you needn’t be cast down if you fail. It’s not an easy
		proposition anyway. That’s all.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence rose.
		</p><p>
		“I think we ought to be businesslike. What exactly can we count upon you
		for, Mr. Carter?” Mr. Carter’s lips twitched slightly, but he
		replied succinctly: “Funds within reason, detailed information on any
		point, and no official recognition. I mean that if you get yourselves
		into trouble with the police, I can’t officially help you out of it.
		You’re on your own.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence nodded sagely.
		</p><p>
		“I quite understand that. I’ll write out a list of the things I
		want to know when I’ve had time to think. Now—about
		money——”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, Miss Tuppence. Do you want to say how much?”
		</p><p>
		“Not exactly. We’ve got plenty to go with for the present, but when
		we want more——”
		</p><p>
		“It will be waiting for you.”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, but—I’m sure I don’t want to be rude about the
		Government if you’ve got anything to do with it, but you know one really
		has the devil of a time getting anything out of it! And if we have to fill up a
		blue form and send it in, and then, after three months, they send us a green
		one, and so on—well, that won’t be much use, will it?”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Carter laughed outright.
		</p><p>
		“Don’t worry, Miss Tuppence. You will send a personal demand to me
		here, and the money, in notes, shall be sent by return of post. As to salary,
		shall we say at the rate of three hundred a year? And an equal sum for Mr.
		Beresford, of course.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence beamed upon him.
		</p><p>
		“How lovely. You are kind. I do love money! I’ll keep beautiful
		accounts of our expenses all debit and credit, and the balance on the right
		side, and red line drawn sideways with the totals the same at the bottom. I
		really know how to do it when I think.”
		</p><p>
		“I’m sure you do. Well, good-bye, and good luck to you both.”
		</p><p>
		He shook hands with them, and in another minute they were descending the steps
		of 27 Carshalton Terrace with their heads in a whirl.
		</p><p>
		“Tommy! Tell me at once, who is ‘Mr. Carter’?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy murmured a name in her ear.
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” said Tuppence, impressed.
		</p><p>
		“And I can tell you, old bean, he’s IT!”
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” said Tuppence again. Then she added reflectively,
		</p><p>
		“I like him, don’t you? He looks so awfully tired and bored, and
		yet you feel that underneath he’s just like steel, all keen and flashing.
		Oh!” She gave a skip. “Pinch me, Tommy, do pinch me. I can’t
		believe it’s real!”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Beresford obliged.
		</p><p>
		“Ow! That’s enough! Yes, we’re not dreaming. We’ve got
		a job!”
		</p><p>
		“And what a job! The joint venture has really begun.”
		</p><p>
		“It’s more respectable than I thought it would be,” said
		Tuppence thoughtfully.
		</p><p>
		“Luckily I haven’t got your craving for crime! What time is it?
		Let’s have lunch—oh!”
		</p><p>
		The same thought sprang to the minds of each. Tommy voiced it first.
		</p><p>
		“Julius P. Hersheimmer!”
		</p><p>
		“We never told Mr. Carter about hearing from him.”
		</p><p>
		“Well, there wasn’t much to tell—not till we’ve seen
		him. Come on, we’d better take a taxi.”
		</p><p>
		“Now who’s being extravagant?”
		</p><p>
		“All expenses paid, remember. Hop in.”
		</p><p>
		“At any rate, we shall make a better effect arriving this way,”
		said Tuppence, leaning back luxuriously. “I’m sure blackmailers
		never arrive in buses!”
		</p><p>
		“We’ve ceased being blackmailers,” Tommy pointed out.
		</p><p>
		“I’m not sure I have,” said Tuppence darkly.
		</p><p>
		On inquiring for Mr. Hersheimmer, they were at once taken up to his suite. An
		impatient voice cried “Come in” in answer to the page-boy’s
		knock, and the lad stood aside to let them pass in.
		</p><p>
		Mr. Julius P. Hersheimmer was a great deal younger than either Tommy or
		Tuppence had pictured him. The girl put him down as thirty-five. He was of
		middle height, and squarely built to match his jaw. His face was pugnacious but
		pleasant. No one could have mistaken him for anything but an American, though
		he spoke with very little accent.
		</p><p>
		“Get my note? Sit down and tell me right away all you know about my
		cousin.”
		</p><p>
		“Your cousin?”
		</p><p>
		“Sure thing. Jane Finn.”
		</p><p>
		“Is she your cousin?”
		</p><p>
		“My father and her mother were brother and sister,” explained Mr.
		Hersheimmer meticulously.
		</p><p>
		“Oh!” cried Tuppence. “Then you know where she is?”
		</p><p>
		“No!” Mr. Hersheimmer brought down his fist with a bang on the
		table. “I’m darned if I do! Don’t you?”
		</p><p>
		“We advertised to receive information, not to give it,” said
		Tuppence severely.
		</p><p>
		“I guess I know that. I can read. But I thought maybe it was her back
		history you were after, and that you’d know where she was now?”
		</p><p>
		“Well, we wouldn’t mind hearing her back history,” said
		Tuppence guardedly.
		</p><p>
		But Mr. Hersheimmer seemed to grow suddenly suspicious.
		</p><p>
		“See here,” he declared. “This isn’t Sicily! No
		demanding ransom or threatening to crop her ears if I refuse. These are the
		British Isles, so quit the funny business, or I’ll just sing out for that
		beautiful big British policeman I see out there in Piccadilly.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy hastened to explain.
		</p><p>
		“We haven’t kidnapped your cousin. On the contrary, we’re
		trying to find her. We’re employed to do so.”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Hersheimmer leant back in his chair.
		</p><p>
		“Put me wise,” he said succinctly.
		</p><p>
		Tommy fell in with this demand in so far as he gave him a guarded version of
		the disappearance of Jane Finn, and of the possibility of her having been mixed
		up unawares in “some political show.” He alluded to Tuppence and
		himself as “private inquiry agents” commissioned to find her, and
		added that they would therefore be glad of any details Mr. Hersheimmer could
		give them.
		</p><p>
		That gentleman nodded approval.
		</p><p>
		“I guess that’s all right. I was just a mite hasty. But London gets
		my goat! I only know little old New York. Just trot out your questions and
		I’ll answer.”
		</p><p>
		For the moment this paralysed the Young Adventurers, but Tuppence, recovering
		herself, plunged boldly into the breach with a reminiscence culled from
		detective fiction.
		</p><p>
		“When did you last see the dece—your cousin, I mean?”
		</p><p>
		“Never seen her,” responded Mr. Hersheimmer.
		</p><p>
		“What?” demanded Tommy, astonished.
		</p><p>
		Hersheimmer turned to him.
		</p><p>
		“No, sir. As I said before, my father and her mother were brother and
		sister, just as you might be”—Tommy did not correct this view of
		their relationship—“but they didn’t always get on together.
		And when my aunt made up her mind to marry Amos Finn, who was a poor school
		teacher out West, my father was just mad! Said if he made his pile, as he
		seemed in a fair way to do, she’d never see a cent of it. Well, the
		upshot was that Aunt Jane went out West and we never heard from her again.
		</p><p>
		“The old man did pile it up. He went into oil, and he went into
		steel, and he played a bit with railroads, and I can tell you he made Wall
		Street sit up!” He paused. “Then he died—last fall—and
		I got the dollars. Well, would you believe it, my conscience got busy! Kept
		knocking me up and saying: What about your Aunt Jane, way out West? It worried
		me some. You see, I figured it out that Amos Finn would never make good. He
		wasn’t the sort. End of it was, I hired a man to hunt her down. Result,
		she was dead, and Amos Finn was dead, but they’d left a
		daughter—Jane—who’d been torpedoed in the Lusitania on
		her way to Paris. She was saved all right, but they didn’t seem able to
		hear of her over this side. I guessed they weren’t hustling any, so I
		thought I’d come along over, and speed things up. I phoned Scotland Yard
		and the Admiralty first thing. The Admiralty rather choked me off, but Scotland
		Yard were very civil—said they would make inquiries, even sent a man
		round this morning to get her photograph. I’m off to Paris to-morrow,
		just to see what the Prefecture is doing. I guess if I go to and fro hustling
		them, they ought to get busy!”
		</p><p>
		The energy of Mr. Hersheimmer was tremendous. They bowed before it.
		</p><p>
		“But say now,” he ended, “you’re not after her for
		anything? Contempt of court, or something British? A proud-spirited young
		American girl might find your rules and regulations in war time rather irksome,
		and get up against it. If that’s the case, and there’s such a thing
		as graft in this country, I’ll buy her off.”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence reassured him.
		</p><p>
		“That’s good. Then we can work together. What about some lunch?
		Shall we have it up here, or go down to the restaurant?”
		</p><p>
		Tuppence expressed a preference for the latter, and Julius bowed to her
		decision.
		</p><p>
		Oysters had just given place to Sole Colbert when a card was brought to
		Hersheimmer.
		</p><p>
		“Inspector Japp, C.I.D. Scotland Yard again. Another man this time. What
		does he expect I can tell him that I didn’t tell the first chap? I hope
		they haven’t lost that photograph. That Western photographer’s
		place was burned down and all his negatives destroyed—this is the only
		copy in existence. I got it from the principal of the college there.”
		</p><p>
		An unformulated dread swept over Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“You—you don’t know the name of the man who came this
		morning?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes, I do. No, I don’t. Half a second. It was on his card. Oh, I
		know! Inspector Brown. Quiet, unassuming sort of chap.”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc7">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER VI.
		A PLAN OF CAMPAIGN</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		A veil might with profit be drawn over the events of the next half-hour.
		Suffice it to say that no such person as “Inspector Brown” was
		known to Scotland Yard. The photograph of Jane Finn, which would have been of
		the utmost value to the police in tracing her, was lost beyond recovery. Once
		again “Mr. Brown” had triumphed.
		</p><p>
		The immediate result of this set-back was to effect a rapprochement
		between Julius Hersheimmer and the Young Adventurers. All barriers went down
		with a crash, and Tommy and Tuppence felt they had known the young American all
		their lives. They abandoned the discreet reticence of “private inquiry
		agents,” and revealed to him the whole history of the joint venture,
		whereat the young man declared himself “tickled to death.”
		</p><p>
		He turned to Tuppence at the close of the narration.
		</p><p>
		“I’ve always had a kind of idea that English girls were just a mite
		moss-grown. Old-fashioned and sweet, you know, but scared to move round without
		a footman or a maiden aunt. I guess I’m a bit behind the times!”
		</p><p>
		The upshot of these confidential relations was that Tommy and Tuppence took up
		their abode forthwith at the Ritz, in order, as Tuppence put it, to keep
		in touch with Jane Finn’s only living relation. “And put like
		that,” she added confidentially to Tommy, “nobody could boggle at
		the expense!”
		</p><p>
		Nobody did, which was the great thing.
		</p><p>
		“And now,” said the young lady on the morning after their
		installation, “to work!”
		</p><p>
		Mr. Beresford put down the Daily Mail, which he was reading, and
		applauded with somewhat unnecessary vigour. He was politely requested by his
		colleague not to be an ass.
		</p><p>
		“Dash it all, Tommy, we’ve got to do something for our
		money.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy sighed.
		</p><p>
		“Yes, I fear even the dear old Government will not support us at the
		Ritz in idleness for ever.”
		</p><p>
		“Therefore, as I said before, we must do something.”
		</p><p>
		“Well,” said Tommy, picking up the Daily Mail again,
		“do it. I shan’t stop you.”
		</p><p>
		“You see,” continued Tuppence. “I’ve been
		thinking——”
		</p><p>
		She was interrupted by a fresh bout of applause.
		</p><p>
		“It’s all very well for you to sit there being funny, Tommy. It
		would do you no harm to do a little brain work too.”
		</p><p>
		“My union, Tuppence, my union! It does not permit me to work before 11
		a.m.”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy, do you want something thrown at you? It is absolutely essential
		that we should without delay map out a plan of campaign.”
		</p><p>
		“Hear, hear!”
		</p><p>
		“Well, let’s do it.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy laid his paper finally aside. “There’s something of the
		simplicity of the truly great mind about you, Tuppence. Fire ahead. I’m
		listening.”
		</p><p>
		“To begin with,” said Tuppence, “what have we to go
		upon?”
		</p><p>
		“Absolutely nothing,” said Tommy cheerily.
		</p><p>
		“Wrong!” Tuppence wagged an energetic finger. “We have two
		distinct clues.”
		</p><p>
		“What are they?”
		</p><p>
		“First clue, we know one of the gang.”
		</p><p>
		“Whittington?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes. I’d recognize him anywhere.”
		</p><p>
		“Hum,” said Tommy doubtfully, “I don’t call that much
		of a clue. You don’t know where to look for him, and it’s about a
		thousand to one against your running against him by accident.”
		</p><p>
		“I’m not so sure about that,” replied Tuppence thoughtfully.
		“I’ve often noticed that once coincidences start happening they go
		on happening in the most extraordinary way. I dare say it’s some natural
		law that we haven’t found out. Still, as you say, we can’t rely on
		that. But there are places in London where simply every one is bound to
		turn up sooner or later. Piccadilly Circus, for instance. One of my ideas was
		to take up my stand there every day with a tray of flags.”
		</p><p>
		“What about meals?” inquired the practical Tommy.
		</p><p>
		“How like a man! What does mere food matter?”
		</p><p>
		“That’s all very well. You’ve just had a thundering good
		breakfast. No one’s got a better appetite than you have, Tuppence, and by
		tea-time you’d be eating the flags, pins and all. But, honestly, I
		don’t think much of the idea. Whittington mayn’t be in London at
		all.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s true. Anyway, I think clue No. 2 is more promising.”
		</p><p>
		“Let’s hear it.”
		</p><p>
		“It’s nothing much. Only a Christian name—Rita. Whittington
		mentioned it that day.”
		</p><p>
		“Are you proposing a third advertisement: Wanted, female crook, answering
		to the name of Rita?”
		</p><p>
		“I am not. I propose to reason in a logical manner. That man, Danvers,
		was shadowed on the way over, wasn’t he? And it’s more likely to
		have been a woman than a man——”
		</p><p>
		“I don’t see that at all.”
		</p><p>
		“I am absolutely certain that it would be a woman, and a good-looking
		one,” replied Tuppence calmly.
		</p><p>
		“On these technical points I bow to your decision,” murmured Mr.
		Beresford.
		</p><p>
		“Now, obviously this woman, whoever she was, was saved.”
		</p><p>
		“How do you make that out?”
		</p><p>
		“If she wasn’t, how would they have known Jane Finn had got the
		papers?”
		</p><p>
		“Correct. Proceed, O Sherlock!”
		</p><p>
		“Now there’s just a chance, I admit it’s only a chance, that
		this woman may have been ‘Rita.’”
		</p><p>
		“And if so?”
		</p><p>
		“If so, we’ve got to hunt through the survivors of the
		Lusitania till we find her.”
		</p><p>
		“Then the first thing is to get a list of the survivors.”
		</p><p>
		“I’ve got it. I wrote a long list of things I wanted to know, and
		sent it to Mr. Carter. I got his reply this morning, and among other things it
		encloses the official statement of those saved from the Lusitania.
		How’s that for clever little Tuppence?”
		</p><p>
		“Full marks for industry, zero for modesty. But the great point is, is
		there a ‘Rita’ on the list?”
		</p><p>
		“That’s just what I don’t know,” confessed Tuppence.
		</p><p>
		“Don’t know?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes. Look here.” Together they bent over the list. “You see,
		very few Christian names are given. They’re nearly all Mrs. or
		Miss.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy nodded.
		</p><p>
		“That complicates matters,” he murmured thoughtfully.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence gave her characteristic “terrier” shake.
		</p><p>
		“Well, we’ve just got to get down to it, that’s all.
		We’ll start with the London area. Just note down the addresses of any of
		the females who live in London or roundabout, while I put on my hat.”
		</p><p>
		Five minutes later the young couple emerged into Piccadilly, and a few seconds
		later a taxi was bearing them to The Laurels, Glendower Road, N.7, the
		residence of Mrs. Edgar Keith, whose name figured first in a list of seven
		reposing in Tommy’s pocket-book.
		</p><p>
		The Laurels was a dilapidated house, standing back from the road with a few
		grimy bushes to support the fiction of a front garden. Tommy paid off the taxi,
		and accompanied Tuppence to the front door bell. As she was about to ring it,
		he arrested her hand.
		</p><p>
		“What are you going to say?”
		</p><p>
		“What am I going to say? Why, I shall say—Oh dear, I don’t
		know. It’s very awkward.”
		</p><p>
		“I thought as much,” said Tommy with satisfaction. “How like
		a woman! No foresight! Now just stand aside, and see how easily the mere male
		deals with the situation.” He pressed the bell. Tuppence withdrew to a
		suitable spot.
		</p><p>
		A slatternly looking servant, with an extremely dirty face and a pair of eyes
		that did not match, answered the door.
		</p><p>
		Tommy had produced a notebook and pencil.
		</p><p>
		“Good morning,” he said briskly and cheerfully. “From the
		Hampstead Borough Council. The new Voting Register. Mrs. Edgar Keith lives
		here, does she not?”
		</p><p>
		“Yaas,” said the servant.
		</p><p>
		“Christian name?” asked Tommy, his pencil poised.
		</p><p>
		“Missus’s? Eleanor Jane.”
		</p><p>
		“Eleanor,” spelt Tommy. “Any sons or daughters over
		twenty-one?”
		</p><p>
		“Naow.”
		</p><p>
		“Thank you.” Tommy closed the notebook with a brisk snap.
		“Good morning.”
		</p><p>
		The servant volunteered her first remark:
		</p><p>
		“I thought perhaps as you’d come about the gas,” she observed
		cryptically, and shut the door.
		</p><p>
		Tommy rejoined his accomplice.
		</p><p>
		“You see, Tuppence,” he observed. “Child’s play to the
		masculine mind.”
		</p><p>
		“I don’t mind admitting that for once you’ve scored
		handsomely. I should never have thought of that.”
		</p><p>
		“Good wheeze, wasn’t it? And we can repeat it ad lib.”
		</p><p>
		Lunch-time found the young couple attacking a steak and chips in an obscure
		hostelry with avidity. They had collected a Gladys Mary and a Marjorie, been
		baffled by one change of address, and had been forced to listen to a long
		lecture on universal suffrage from a vivacious American lady whose Christian
		name had proved to be Sadie.
		</p><p>
		“Ah!” said Tommy, imbibing a long draught of beer, “I feel
		better. Where’s the next draw?”
		</p><p>
		The notebook lay on the table between them. Tuppence picked it up.
		</p><p>
		“Mrs. Vandemeyer,” she read, “20 South Audley Mansions. Miss
		Wheeler, 43 Clapington Road, Battersea. She’s a lady’s maid, as far
		as I remember, so probably won’t be there, and, anyway, she’s not
		likely.”
		</p><p>
		“Then the Mayfair lady is clearly indicated as the first port of
		call.”
		</p><p>
		“Tommy, I’m getting discouraged.”
		</p><p>
		“Buck up, old bean. We always knew it was an outside chance. And, anyway,
		we’re only starting. If we draw a blank in London, there’s a fine
		tour of England, Ireland and Scotland before us.”
		</p><p>
		“True,” said Tuppence, her flagging spirits reviving. “And
		all expenses paid! But, oh, Tommy, I do like things to happen quickly. So far,
		adventure has succeeded adventure, but this morning has been dull as
		dull.”
		</p><p>
		“You must stifle this longing for vulgar sensation, Tuppence. Remember
		that if Mr. Brown is all he is reported to be, it’s a wonder that he has
		not ere now done us to death. That’s a good sentence, quite a literary
		flavour about it.”
		</p><p>
		“You’re really more conceited than I am—with less excuse!
		Ahem! But it certainly is queer that Mr. Brown has not yet wreaked vengeance
		upon us. (You see, I can do it too.) We pass on our way unscathed.”
		</p><p>
		“Perhaps he doesn’t think us worth bothering about,”
		suggested the young man simply.
		</p><p>
		Tuppence received the remark with great disfavour.
		</p><p>
		“How horrid you are, Tommy. Just as though we didn’t count.”
		</p><p>
		“Sorry, Tuppence. What I meant was that we work like moles in the dark,
		and that he has no suspicion of our nefarious schemes. Ha ha!”
		</p><p>
		“Ha ha!” echoed Tuppence approvingly, as she rose.
		</p><p>
		South Audley Mansions was an imposing-looking block of flats just off Park
		Lane. No. 20 was on the second floor.
		</p><p>
		Tommy had by this time the glibness born of practice. He rattled off the
		formula to the elderly woman, looking more like a housekeeper than a servant,
		who opened the door to him.
		</p><p>
		“Christian name?”
		</p><p>
		“Margaret.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy spelt it, but the other interrupted him.
		</p><p>
		“No, g u e.”
		</p><p>
		“Oh, Marguerite; French way, I see.” He paused, then plunged
		boldly. “We had her down as Rita Vandemeyer, but I suppose that’s
		incorrect?”
		</p><p>
		“She’s mostly called that, sir, but Marguerite’s her
		name.”
		</p><p>
		“Thank you. That’s all. Good morning.”
		</p><p>
		Hardly able to contain his excitement, Tommy hurried down the stairs. Tuppence
		was waiting at the angle of the turn.
		</p><p>
		“You heard?”
		</p><p>
		“Yes. Oh, Tommy!”
		</p><p>
		Tommy squeezed her arm sympathetically.
		</p><p>
		“I know, old thing. I feel the same.”
		</p><p>
		“It’s—it’s so lovely to think of things—and then
		for them really to happen!” cried Tuppence enthusiastically.
		</p><p>
		Her hand was still in Tommy’s. They had reached the entrance hall. There
		were footsteps on the stairs above them, and voices.
		</p><p>
		Suddenly, to Tommy’s complete surprise, Tuppence dragged him into the
		little space by the side of the lift where the shadow was deepest.
		</p><p>
		“What the——”
		</p><p>
		“Hush!”
		</p><p>
		Two men came down the stairs and passed out through the entrance.
		Tuppence’s hand closed tighter on Tommy’s arm.
		</p><p>
		“Quick—follow them. I daren’t. He might recognize me. I
		don’t know who the other man is, but the bigger of the two was
		Whittington.”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>
		<book-part id="tc8">
			<book-part-meta>
				<title-group>
					<title>CHAPTER VII.
		THE HOUSE IN SOHO</title>
				</title-group>
			</book-part-meta>
			<body>
				<p>

		Whittington and his companion were walking at a good pace. Tommy started in
		pursuit at once, and was in time to see them turn the corner of the street. His
		vigorous strides soon enabled him to gain upon them, and by the time he, in his
		turn, reached the corner the distance between them was sensibly lessened. The
		small Mayfair streets were comparatively deserted, and he judged it wise to
		content himself with keeping them in sight.
		</p><p>
		The sport was a new one to him. Though familiar with the technicalities from a
		course of novel reading, he had never before attempted to “follow”
		anyone, and it appeared to him at once that, in actual practice, the proceeding
		was fraught with difficulties. Supposing, for instance, that they should
		suddenly hail a taxi? In books, you simply leapt into another, promised the
		driver a sovereign—or its modern equivalent—and there you were. In
		actual fact, Tommy foresaw that it was extremely likely there would be no
		second taxi. Therefore he would have to run. What happened in actual fact to a
		young man who ran incessantly and persistently through the London streets? In a
		main road he might hope to create the illusion that he was merely running for a
		bus. But in these obscure aristocratic byways he could not but feel that an
		officious policeman might stop him to explain matters.
		</p><p>
		At this juncture in his thoughts a taxi with flag erect turned the corner of
		the street ahead. Tommy held his breath. Would they hail it?
		</p><p>
		He drew a sigh of relief as they allowed it to pass unchallenged. Their course
		was a zigzag one designed to bring them as quickly as possible to Oxford
		Street. When at length they turned into it, proceeding in an easterly
		direction, Tommy slightly increased his pace. Little by little he gained upon
		them. On the crowded pavement there was little chance of his attracting their
		notice, and he was anxious if possible to catch a word or two of their
		conversation. In this he was completely foiled; they spoke low and the din of
		the traffic drowned their voices effectually.
		</p><p>
		Just before the Bond Street Tube station they crossed the road, Tommy,
		unperceived, faithfully at their heels, and entered the big Lyons’. There
		they went up to the first floor, and sat at a small table in the window. It was
		late, and the place was thinning out. Tommy took a seat at the table next to
		them, sitting directly behind Whittington in case of recognition. On the other
		hand, he had a full view of the second man and studied him attentively. He was
		fair, with a weak, unpleasant face, and Tommy put him down as being either a
		Russian or a Pole. He was probably about fifty years of age, his shoulders
		cringed a little as he talked, and his eyes, small and crafty, shifted
		unceasingly.
		</p><p>
		Having already lunched heartily, Tommy contented himself with ordering a Welsh
		rarebit and a cup of coffee. Whittington ordered a substantial lunch for
		himself and his companion; then, as the waitress withdrew, he moved his chair a
		little closer to the table and began to talk earnestly in a low voice. The
		other man joined in. Listen as he would, Tommy could only catch a word here and
		there; but the gist of it seemed to be some directions or orders which the big
		man was impressing on his companion, and with which the latter seemed from time
		to time to disagree. Whittington addressed the other as Boris.
		</p><p>
		Tommy caught the word “Ireland” several times, also
		“propaganda,” but of Jane Finn there was no mention. Suddenly, in a
		lull in the clatter of the room, he got one phrase entire. Whittington was
		speaking. “Ah, but you don’t know Flossie. She’s a marvel. An
		archbishop would swear she was his own mother. She gets the voice right every
		time, and that’s really the principal thing.”
		</p><p>
		Tommy did not hear Boris’s reply, but in response to it Whittington said
		something that sounded like: “Of course—only in an
		emergency....”
		</p><p>
		Then he lost the thread again. But presently the phrases became distinct again
		whether because the other two had insensibly raised their voices, or because
		Tommy’s ears were getting more attuned, he could not tell. But two words
		certainly had a most stimulating effect upon the listener. They were uttered by
		Boris and they were: “Mr. Brown.”
		</p><p>
		Whittington seemed to remonstrate with him, but he merely laughed.
		</p><p>
		“Why not, my friend? It is a name most respectable—most common. Did
		he not choose it for that reason? Ah, I should like to meet him—Mr.
		Brown.”
		</p><p>
		There was a steely ring in Whittington’s voice as he replied:
		</p><p>
		“Who knows? You may have met him already.”
		</p><p>
		“Bah!” retorted the other. “That is children’s
		talk—a fable for the police. Do you know what I say to myself sometimes?
		That he is a fable invented by the Inner Ring, a bogy to frighten us with. It
		might be so.”
		</p><p>
		“And it might not.”
		</p><p>
		“I wonder ... or is it indeed true that he is with us and amongst us,
		unknown to all but a chosen few? If so, he keeps his secret well. And the idea
		is a good one, yes. We never know. We look at each other— one of us is
		Mr. Brown—which? He commands—but also he serves. Among
		us—in the midst of us. And no one knows which he is....”
		</p><p>
		With an effort the Russian shook off the vagary of his fancy. He looked at his
		watch.
		</p><p>
		“Yes,” said Whittington. “We might as well go.”
		</p><p>
		He called the waitress and asked for his bill. Tommy did likewise, and a few
		moments later was following the two men down the stairs.
		</p><p>
		Outside, Whittington hailed a taxi, and directed the driver to go to Waterloo.
		</p><p>
		Taxis were plentiful here, and before Whittington’s had driven off
		another was drawing up to the curb in obedience to Tommy’s peremptory
		hand.
		</p><p>
		“Follow that other taxi,” directed the young man.
		“Don’t lose it.”
		</p><p>
		The elderly chauffeur showed no interest. He merely grunted and jerked down his
		flag. The drive was uneventful. Tommy’s taxi came to rest at the
		departure platform just after Whittington’s. Tommy was behind him at the
		booking-office. He took a first-class single ticket to Bournemouth, Tommy did
		the same. As he emerged, Boris remarked, glancing up at the clock: “You
		are early. You have nearly half an hour.”
		</p><p>
		Boris’s words had aroused a new train of thought in Tommy’s mind.
		Clearly Whittington was making the journey alone, while the other remained in
		London. Therefore he was left with a choice as to which he would follow.
		Obviously, he could not follow both of them unless—— Like Boris, he
		glanced up at the clock, and then to the announcement board of the trains. The
		Bournemouth train left at 3.30. It was now ten past. Whittington and Boris were
		walking up and down by the bookstall. He gave one doubtful look at them, then
		hurried into an adjacent telephone box. He dared not waste time in trying to
		get hold of Tuppence. In all probability she was still in the neighbourhood of
		South Audley Mansions. But there remained another ally. He rang up the
		Ritz and asked for Julius Hersheimmer. There was a click and a buzz. Oh,
		if only the young American was in his room! There was another click, and then
		“Hello” in unmistakable accents came over the wire.
		</p><p>
		“That you, Hersheimmer? Beresford speaking. I’m at Waterloo.
		I’ve followed Whittington and another man here. No time to explain.
		Whittington’s off to Bournemouth by the 3.30. Can you get there by
		then?”
		</p><p>
		The reply was reassuring.
		</p><p>
		“Sure. I’ll hustle.”
		</p><p>
		The telephone rang off. Tommy put back the receiver with a sigh of relief. His
		opinion of Julius’s power of hustling was high. He felt instinctively
		that the American would arrive in time.
		</p><p>
		Whittington and Boris were still where he had left them. If Boris remained to
		see his friend off, all was well. Then Tommy fingered his pocket thoughtfully.
		In spite of the carte blanche assured to him, he had not yet acquired the habit
		of going about with any considerable sum of money on him. The taking of the
		first-class ticket to Bournemouth had left him with only a few shillings in his
		pocket. It was to be hoped that Julius would arrive better provided.
		</p><p>
		In the meantime, the minutes were creeping by: 3.15, 3.20, 3.25, 3.27.
		Supposing Julius did not get there in time. 3.29.... Doors were banging. Tommy
		felt cold waves of despair pass over him. Then a hand fell on his shoulder.
		</p><p>
		“Here I am, son. Your British traffic beats description! Put me wise to
		the crooks right away.”
		</p><p>
		“That’s Whittington—there, getting in now, that big dark man.
		The other is the foreign chap he’s talking to.”
		</p><p>
		“I’m on to them. Which of the two is my bird?”
		</p><p>
		Tommy had thought out this question.
		</p><p>
		“Got any money with you?”
		</p><p>
		Julius shook his head, and Tommy’s face fell.
		</p><p>
		“I guess I haven’t more than three or four hundred dollars with me
		at the moment,” explained the American.
		</p><p>
		Tommy gave a faint whoop of relief.
		</p><p>
		“Oh, Lord, you millionaires! You don’t talk the same language!
		Climb aboard the lugger. Here’s your ticket. Whittington’s your
		man.”
		</p><p>
		“Me for Whittington!” said Julius darkly. The train was just
		starting as he swung himself aboard. “So long, Tommy.” The train
		slid out of the station.
		</p><p>
		Tommy drew a deep breath. The man Boris was coming along the platform towards
		him. Tommy allowed him to pass and then took up the chase once more.
		</p><p>
		From Waterloo Boris took the tube as far as Piccadilly Circus. Then he walked
		up Shaftesbury Avenue, finally turning off into the maze of mean streets round
		Soho. Tommy followed him at a judicious distance.
		</p><p>
		They reached at length a small dilapidated square. The houses there had a
		sinister air in the midst of their dirt and decay. Boris looked round, and
		Tommy drew back into the shelter of a friendly porch. The place was almost
		deserted. It was a cul-de-sac, and consequently no traffic passed that way. The
		stealthy way the other had looked round stimulated Tommy’s imagination.
		From the shelter of the doorway he watched him go up the steps of a
		particularly evil-looking house and rap sharply, with a peculiar rhythm, on the
		door. It was opened promptly, he said a word or two to the doorkeeper, then
		passed inside. The door was shut to again.
		</p><p>
		It was at this juncture that Tommy lost his head. What he ought to have done,
		what any sane man would have done, was to remain patiently where he was and
		wait for his man to come out again. What he did do was entirely foreign to the
		sober common sense which was, as a rule, his leading characteristic. Something,
		as he expressed it, seemed to snap in his brain. Without a moment’s pause
		for reflection he, too, went up the steps, and reproduced as far as he was able
		the peculiar knock.
		</p><p>
		The door swung open with the same promptness as before. A villainous-faced man
		with close-cropped hair stood in the doorway.
		</p><p>
		“Well?” he grunted.
		</p><p>
		It was at that moment that the full realization of his folly began to come home
		to Tommy. But he dared not hesitate. He seized at the first words that came
		into his mind.
		</p><p>
		“Mr. Brown?” he said.
		</p><p>
		To his surprise the man stood aside.
		</p><p>
		“Upstairs,” he said, jerking his thumb over his shoulder,
		“second door on your left.”

				</p>
			</body>
		</book-part>

    </book-body>
</book>
